Summary of Qualifications

An accomplished Computer Networks Operations professional with over 8 years of experience leading multiple mission efforts to meet high priority US Navy, US Army and National Requirements; seeking technical job roles to further expertise and experience as well as challenge myself within the cyber domain.

Clearance: Top Secret/SCI with CI Polygraph

Experience

CNO Exploitation Analyst Trainer at NetSage Corporation

01/2022 to Present, Columbia, MD

- Instruct students in a formal classroom environment on various complex technical computer and networking topics in support of Computer Network Operations (CNO) analysis.
- Continuously create, modify, and add content to current course curriculum to best reflect current technological, legal, and customer requirements.
- Develop and evaluate assessment questions and scenarios to gauge student understanding of Computer Network Exploitation (CNE) concepts.
- Create and configure virtual hosts and networking using VMware in support of developing real-world scenarios via vSphere.

Senior Exploitation Analyst and Trainer at USCYBERCOM

08/2018 to 09/2021; Navy Information Operations Command Georgia, Fort Gordon, GA

- Project Lead for multiple Lines of Effort. Led and/or managed the execution of over 100 computer network operations spanning between six projects and two Combat Mission Teams.
- Senior Trainer for ARCYBER/JFHQ-C. Created a training program to increase qualification rate for new accessions and provide more workforce assets for entire branch.
- Supervised and mentored junior joint-servicemen and women as a Non-commissioned officer.
- Consistently conducted quick response analysis in support of world crisis events; efficiently managed and executed operations in support of CENTCOM's highest priority interests.
- Briefed senior officials/officers on the progress of critical network analysis projects and computer network operations.

Exploitation Analyst and Trainer at National Security Agency-Hawaii

07/2015 to 08/2018; Navy Information Operations Command Hawaii, Wahiawa, HI

- Project Lead. Conducted over 100 computer network operations to perform and enable collection of Foreign Intelligence in support of national security and US military requirements.
- Built network maps to visualize logical layouts of target networks.
- Drafted technical plans to conduct on-net cyber operations.
- Identified logical and physical security controls, analyzed information system defense posture, and conducted full risk assessments
- Tailored searches to efficiently query data warehouses for relevant information
- Managed administrative and technical training for section.

Initial Entry Trainee – US Navy

12/2014 to 07/2015; CID Corry Station, Pensacola, FL

- Learned and exercised full scope Computer Network Operations in a lab environment
- Completed Joint Cyber Analysis Course (JCAC) with Honors, which encompasses:
 - o Systems Administration for Windows, *nix, and Cisco devices

- o Computational Mathematics
- o C Programming & BASH/Python scripting
- o Network Traffic Analysis and Threat Detection
- o Network Reconnaissance and Penetration Testing
- o Malware Analysis

Boatswain's Mate - US Navy

12/2012 to 12/2014; USS George Washington (CVN-73), Yokosuka, Japan

- Rigger for all deck evolutions, to include Underway Replenishment (Cargo, Food and Fuel)
- On-Scene leader for General Quarters/Damage Control Situations. Directed Firefighting, Flooding and Collision efforts in response to emergency casualties.
- Drove over 5,000 nautical miles as helmsman for aircraft carrier in the Western Pacific Ocean.
- Qualified six people in watch standing responsibilities as Over Instructor for watch section.

Technical Expertise

- Linux Operating Systems 6 yrs
- Windows Operating Systems 6 yrs
- Network Enumeration 6 yrs
- Vulnerability Analysis 6 yrs
- Packet Analysis/Wireshark 6 yrs
- Microsoft Office (Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Visio)
 6 yrs
- VMware 6 yrs
- Kali Linux/Metasploit 6 yrs
- Cisco/MikroTik 6 yrs
- TCP/IP Network Design 6 yrs
- Ticketing Systems 6 yrs
- HeidiSQL (6 months)
- WinSCP (6 months)
- Moodle LMS (6 months)

Education

University of Maryland Global Campus - Adelphi, MD

2016 to Current

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Networks and Cybersecurity; expected DEC 2023

National Cryptologic School

2015 to Current; full transcript available on request

Completed over 750 hours of course-work; courses of note include:

- Requirements and Targeting Immersion Program (CYBR3800) (02/2016)
- NET+ Boot Camp (12/2017)
- SEC+ Boot Camp (08/2017)
- Certified Ethical Hacker (08/2020)
- CCNA Boot Camp (03/2018)
- Analytic Tradecraft Fundamentals (NETA2108) (12/2015)

References available upon Request

Case number (RES-2022-06297)